American Vaudeville Museum collection, 1850s-2007 (bulk 1910s-1940s)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series XXXII: LP Record Collection, American Vaudeville Museum, 11.3 linear feet (Box 85-107)
  - Subseries 10: LP Records: Hollywood Musicals
    - Golden Age of the Hollywood Musical - The Kay Thompson Reviews (Box 102)
      Hooray for Hollywood: The Golden Age of the Hollywood Musical (with booklet); Frances Langford, Johnny "Scat" Davis, Dick Powell, Bebe Daniels, Wini Shaw, Judy Canova, Lee Dixon, Joan Blondell, Rosalind Marquis, Ruby Keeler, Una Merkel, Ginger Rogers and Vera Teasdale. 1975 reissue by United Artists UA-LA361-H-0798
      Ladies of Burlesque (compilation of clips by Alice Faye, Grace Bradley, Glenda Farrell, Miriam Hopkins, Ann Sothern, Virginia O'Brien, Marion Martin, Lucille Ball, Constance Moore, Ann Miller, Iris Adrian, Barbara Stanwyck, Betty Grable, Marilyn Monroe, Nita Talbot, Adele Jergens, Shelley Winters, Ann Sheridan, Jan Sterling, Kathryn Grayson, Jane Wyman, Rita Hayworth, Joanne Woodward & Cara Williams. Legends Records-1000/2
      Stars of the Silver Screen, 1929-1930: John Boles, Fanny Brice, Maurice Chevalier, Bebe Daniels, Dolores Del Rio, Duncan Sisters, George Jessel, Helen Kane, Charles King, Dennis King, Jeanette MacDonald, Everett Marshall, Helen Morgan, Gloria Swanson, Sophie Tucker and Lupe Velez. RCA Victor LPV-538
      Nostalgia Trip to the Stars, volume 1: Tallulah Bankhead, Jack Buchanan, George Burns & Gracie Allen, Jackie Coogan, Bebe Daniels, Jeanette MacDonald, Pola Negri, Ramon Navarro and Gloria Swanson. Monmouth Evergreen MES-7030
      Nostalgia Trip to the Stars, volume 2: Bebe Daniels & Ben Lyon, Gracie Fields, Stanley Holloway, Elsa Lanchester, Laurel & Hardy, Adolphe Menjou, Anna Neagle, Lilli Palmer, Walter Pidgeon, Harry Richman and Sophie Tucker. Monmouth Evergreen MES-7031
      The Kay Thompson Reviews: Bing Crosby, Peter Lorre, Jack Buchanan and others. Ultimo KAYT 406A
  - Subseries 11: LP Records: Spoken Word Recordings - Classic Actors
    - Great Actors of the Past - Ralph Richardson, Cyrano de Bergerac (Box 102)
      Great Actors of the Past: cylinder recordings by Edwin Booth (1890), Joseph Jefferson (1903), Sarah Bernhardt (1910), Constant Coquelin (1897?), Ellen Terry (1911), Henry Irving (1890), Beerbohm Tree (?), Julia Nelson & Fred Terry (1903?), Alexander Moissi (?), Cyril Maude (?), Lewis Waller (?) and Tomasso Salvini (?); 1977, Decca Argo SW-510
      American National Theatre & Academy, ANTA Album of Stars, volume 2: Katherine Cornell, Brian Ahearn, Julie Harris, Henry Fonda, Marc Connelly, Edith Evans, Torin Thatcher, Ivan Sampson, Tallulah Bankhead, Kent Smith, Eugenia Rawls; 1950s, Decca DL 9009
      Command Performance, Night of a Thousand Stars: 28 June 1956. Edith Evans, Peggy Ashcroft, Paul Scofield, Peter Ustinov, Lawrence Harvey, Jack Benny, Yvonne Larvin, John Mills, Vivien Leigh, Bob Hope, Tyrone Power, Laurence Olivier, Anna Massey, Sheila Sim, Noel Coward, Joan Sims, Jean Kent, cie Gray, Brenda Bruce, Peggy Cummins, Beatrice Lillie, Tallulah Bankhead, Mabel Mercer and Thelma Ruby. (same LP) Royal Variety Performance: 1952: Vera Lynn, Jack Jackson, Reg Dixon, Gracie Fields, Maurice Chevalier, issued 1977 DRG ArchiveDARC-1-1106
      John Barrymore: Great Profile Speaks, Richard III & movie role excerpts, Shakepox J Bar 42
      John Gielgud: Shakespeare's Ages of Man, 1958-59, Columbia 91A-02055
      John Gielgud: Shakespeare's Ages of Man, part II: One Man in His Time, 1958-59, Columbia 91A-02057
      John Gielgud & Irene Worth, Men and Women of Shakespeare, 1967?, RCA Victor VDM-115
      John Gielgud & Gina Bachauer, poetry & music (Debussy & Ravel), 1964, Mercury SR-90391
      Edith Evans: An 18th Century Comedy Album, excerpts: Congreve's Way of the World, Farquhar's The Beaux' Stratagem and Sheridan's The Rivals and The School for Scandal, 1977, EMI/HMV HLM-7108
      Michael MacLiammoir: The Importance of Being Oscar, Part II, 1961?, CBS Classics 61160
      Art of Ruth Draper, volume 2: Church in Italy & English House Party, 1954, Spoken Arts 798
      Art of Ruth Draper, volume 5: Doctors & Diets, The Actress, 1954, Spoken Arts Records 805
      Ralph Richardson: Cyrano de Bergerac, with Anna Massey, Peter Wyngard, 3 LPs, 1965?, Caedmon/Theatre Recording Society TRS-3068-S
  - Subseries 12: LP Records: Spoken Word Recordings - Miscellany
    - Nonsense Verse of Lewis Carroll and Edward Lear – Voices from the Hollywood Past (Box 103)
      Beatrice Lillie, Cyril Ritchard & Stanley Holloway read Nonsense Verse of Lewis Carroll and Edward Lear, 1957, Caedmon Publishers Records TC-1078
      The World of Dorothy Parker, [Dorothy Parker] Reads Her Short Stories, Verse and a Book Review, 1960s, Verve V-15029
      S. J. Perelman Reads (4 humorous essays), 1962, Spoken Arts Records 705
      An Evening with Quentin Crisp: The Naked Civil Servant, 1979, DRG-S2L-5188
      Mary Pickford: America's Sweetheart; radio broadcasts 1938-1968, Garabedian Mark 56 #703
      Movie Stars on Radio (4 LP set): Bette Davis, Spencer Tracey, Rosalind Russell, Henry Fonda, Paulette Goddard, Lloyd Nolan, Walter Brennan, Cary Grant, Judy Garland, Dick Powell, Gene Kelly, Marlene Dietrich, John Wayne, Randolph Scott, Dame May Whitty, Edward G. Robinson, Vincent Price, Susan Hayward and Charles Boyer. 1940-47, issued 1983 by Radiola Records 4MR-1
      Prairie Home Companion: Garrison Keillor, The Family Radio, 1982, PHC Records-606
      Old Curiosity Shop, 1951? reissue, RCA Victor LCT-1112 (dupe LP in Vaudeville Collection)
      Supper Club Revue with Harry Ritz, Sophie Tucker, Skinnay Innis & Orchestra, etc., 1950s, reissued 1981, American Entertainment, AEI-1135
      Voices from the Hollywood Past: Basil Rathbone (1958), Buster Keaton (1960), Stanley Laurel (1959), Harold Lloyd (?), Walt Disney (1959) and Edward G. Robinson (1964), issued 1975 by Delos Records DEL/F-25412
  - Subseries 13: LP Records: Spoken Word Recordings - Comedians, Solo or Teams
    - Bryan – Williams (Box 103)
      Bert and I and Other Stories from Down East, Robert Bryan & Marshall Dodge, 1958
      George Carlin: Occupation: Foole, 1973, Little David LD-1005
      Cheech & Chong (self-titled), 1972, ODE Records SP-77010
      Cheech & Chong: Big Bambu, 1972, ODE Records SP-77014
      Cheech & Chong: Out of My Room, 1985, MCA Records-5640
      The Beautiful Phyllis Diller, 1962?, MGM/Verve V6-15062
      Stepin Fetchit in Person, 1961, Vee Jay LP-1032
      Firesign Theatre: Waiting for the Electrician or Someone Like Him, 1968, Columbia CS-9518
      Firesign Theatre: Don't Crush that Dwarf; Hand Me the Plyers, 1970, Columbia 30101
      An Evening with Mike Nichols & Elaine May, 1960, Mercury Records OCS-6200
      Nichols & May: Improvisations to Music, 1959, Mercury SR-60040
      Best of Nichols & May, 1960s, Mercury SR-60997
      Richard Pryor: That Nigger's Crazy, 1974, Warner Bros./Reprise Records MS 2241
      Lily Tomlin: Modern Scream, 1975, Polydor Records PD-6051
      Robin Williams: Reality - What a Concept, 1979, Casablanca Records, NBLP-7162
  - Subseries 14: LP Records: Folk Music - Solo Singers or Family Acts
    - Belafonte - Washington (Box 104)
      Harry Belafonte, Mark Twain & Other Folk Favorites, 1954, RCA Victor LPM-1022
      Oscar Brand, American Drinking Songs (with Erik Darling), 1956, Riverside RLP-12-630
      Roll Cahn & Eric Von Schmidt (also name of the LP), 1961, Folkways Records FA 2417
      Original and Great Carter Family, reissued 1962 by RCA Camden CAL-586
      Charles River Valley Boys, Bluegrass/Old Timey Music, 1962, Prestige Folklore-14017
      Judy Collins, In My Life, 1966, Elektra Records, EKS-7320
      Bob Dylan (produced by John Hammond), 1962, Columbia CL-1779
      Bob Dylan, Times They Are A-Changing, 1962-63?, Columbia CL-8905
      Bob Dylan, Freewheelin', 1963, Columbia CL-1986
      Bob Dylan, John Wesley Harding, 1967, Columbia CL-9604
      Bonnie Dobson, She's Like a Swallow, 1962?, Prestige International-13021 (2 copies)
      Cynthia Gooding, Languages of Love, 1958, Riverside RLP-12-827
      Arlo Guthrie, Running Down the Road, 1969, Reprise Records 6346
      Carolyn Hester (self-titled), 1962, Columbia Records CL-1796
      Jim Kweskin & The Jug Band (also title), 1963, Vanguard, VRS-9139
      Ewan MacColl & A.L. Lloyd, A Sailor's Garland, 1962?, Prestige International 13043
      Peggy Seeger & Ewan MacColl, A Lover's Garland, 1963?, Prestige International 13061
      Ewan MacColl & Peggy Seeger, New Briton Gazette, 1962, Folkways Records FW-734
      Country Joe McDonald, Animal Tracks, 1983, Animus/Feel-1
      Geoff Muldaur ( Fritz Richmond, etc.), Sleepy Man Blues, 1963, Prestige Folklore 14004
      Susan Reed (also title), 1957, Elektra EKL-116
      Tom Rush at The Unicorn, 1962, LyCornu Records SA-70 (?)
      Tony Saleton, I'm a Stranger Here, 1962?, Prestige International INT-13036
      Peggy Seeger with Barbara & Penny Seeger, Three Sisters, 1962, Prestige International 13029
      Pete Seeger, Sing Out with Pete, 1961, Folkways Records FA-2455
      Mark Spoelstra Recorded at Club 47, 1963, Folkways Records FG-3572
      Sister Rosetta Tharpe, The Gospel Truth, 1961, Verve, V/V6-8439
      Dave Van Ronk Sings Ballads & a Spiritual, 1959, Folkways Records FS-3818
      Jackie Washington (also title), 1962, Vanguard VRS-9141
      Jackie Washington, volume 2 (with Fritz Richmond), 1963, Vanguard VRS-9141
  - Subseries 15: LP Records: Folk Music - Compilations
    - Folk Festival at Newport, 1959 – Southern Journey 12: Honor the Lamb (Box 104)
      Folk Festival at Newport, 1959, Joan Baez & Bob Gibson, Barbara Dane, New Lost City Ramblers, Odetta, Mike Seeger, Sonny Terry & Brownie McGhee, Vanguard, VSD-2054
      New Folks, volume 2, Phil Ochs, Eric Anderson, Lisa Kindred, Bob Jones, 1964, Vanguard VRS-9140
      Alan Lomax Field Recordings:
      Southern Journey: All Day Singing from the Sacred Harp, 1959-1960, Prestige Int'l-25007
      Southern Journey 11: Southern White Spirituals, 1959-1960, Prestige International-25011
      Southern Journey 12: Honor the Lamb, 1959-1960, Prestige International-25012
  - Subseries 16: LP Records: Instrumentalists - Blues (mostly solos) and Jazz (mostly small combos)
    - Armstrong – Handy (Box 105)
      Louis Armstrong:
      Louis Armstrong & His All Star in Concert (2 LPs), 1977, Crescendo GNPS-11001
      Louis Armstrong & His Hot Five, 1925-1927, reissued 1955-60 by Columbia CL-851
      The Great Louis Armstrong (King Oliver Band, 1923), remastered 1968 Orpheum #105
      Satchmo at Pasadena, Louis Armstrong & the All Stars, 1951, Decca DL-8041
      Sidney Bechet:
      Complete Sidney Bechet, volumes 3 & 4, 1941, RCA Jazz Tribune (France) PM-43262
      Bechet of New Orleans, recorded in USA 1940-41, reissued 1957 & 1980, Pickwick Quintessence QJ-25411
      Genius of Sidney Bechet, 1947, reissued 1970s/80s by GHB/Jazzology J-35
      Sidney Bechet with Claude Luter & His Orchestra; volume 25 Concerts: Salle Pleyel, Disques Vogue LD-554-30
      Fabulous Sidney Bechet with Sidney de Paris & Jonah Jones, 1951-53, Bluenote 81207
      Sidney Bechet & Mezz Messrow, 1945-47, reissued 1976, 2 LPS, Classic Jazz, CJ-28
      Bunny Berrigan: I Can't Get Started, 1937-39 on Camden & RCA, reissued 1978 by Pickwick Quintessence QJ-25081
      Scrapper Blackwell, Mr. Scrapper's Blues, 1961, Bluesville 1047
      Eubie Blake, Rags to Classics, 1971, Eubie Blake Music label, EBM-2
      Wilbur de Paris & His New Orleans Jazz, Marchin' and Swingin', 1952, Atlantic 1233
      Baby Dodds Trio, Jazz a la Creole, 1946 & 1951, Circle Records, with James P. Johnson, Albert Nicholas, Pops Foster, Don Ewell & Danny Barker; reissued by George Buck as GHB-50
      K.C. Douglas Blues, late 1950s/early 1960s, Prestige/Bluesville-1023
      Duke Ellington at the Cotton Club, 1937-38, with Ivie Anderson, Swedish reissue: TAX m-8001
      The Early Duke Ellington, with Jimmy Dorsey & Una Mae Carlisle, reissued by Everest FS-221
      Gershwin by [George] Gershwin, radio broadcasts 1931-35, 2 LPs, reissued 1973, Mark 56-641
      Edmund Hall Quintets, Celestial Express, 1941 & 1944, Blue Note B-6505, autographed by Edmund Hall & Winnie Hall (his wife)
      W.C. Handy, Father of the Blues, St Louis Blues, sings his compositions and talks, recorded in the early 1950s; reissued 1975 by Garabedian Mark 56 as #684
    - Hines – Kenton (Box 106)
      Earl Hines, Paris Sessions, piano solos, 1965, reissued in 1981 by Inner City Records IC-1142
      Earl Hines in New Orleans, 1977, solo piano, Chiaroscuro Records CR-200
      Earl Hines Quintessential Continued, mid-1970s, solo piano, Chiaroscuro CR-120
      [Earl] Hines Comes in Handy, piano solos of W.C. Handy's music, 1973, Audiophile AP-112
      [Earl] Hines Does Hoagy [Carmichael], piano solos, 1974, reissue 1982 Audiophile AP-113
      Hines: My Tribute to Louis [Armstrong], piano solos of 1971 issued 1973, Audiophile-AP-111
      Shakey Jake: Mouth Harp Blues with combo, early 1960s?, Prestige/Bluesville 1027
      Immortal Blind Lemon Jefferson (volume 1), 1926-29, reissued 1967 Milestone MLP-2004
      Immortal Blind Lemon Jefferson (volume 2), 1926-29, reissued 1968 Milestone MLP-2007
      Original James P. Johnson, piano solos 1943-45, reissued 1973 Folkways Records FJ-2850
      Robert Johnson: King of the Delta Blues Singers, 1936?, reissued 1970s? Columbia C-30034
      Dr. John Plays Mac Rebennack, piano solos, 1981, Clear Cut Records CC-705
      Uncollected Stan Kenton, volume 3, radio broadcasts 1943-44, reissued 1979 HindsightHSR-136
      Uncollected Stan Kenton, volume 4, radio broadcasts 1944-45, reissued 1979 HindsightHSR-147
      Stan Kenton: Artistry in Rhythm, 1952-54?, reissued ? by EMI-Capitol SM-167
  - Subseries 17: LP Records: Instrumentalists - Blues (mostly solos) and Jazz (combos)
    - Larkins - Mulligan (Box 106)
      Ellis Larkins, solo piano, 1980, Island Records/Digital Records, DBT-101
      Leadbelly Sings Folk Songs, with Woody Guthrie, Cisco Houston, Sonny Terry & Brownie McGhee, reissued 1962, Folkways Records FA-2488
      Leadbelly's Last Sessions, 1953, Part One, Folkways Records FA-2941 A & B
      Leadbelly's Last Sessions, 1953, Part Three, Folkways Records FA-2942 A & B
      Leadbelly's Last Sessions, 1953, Part Four, Folkways Records FA-2942 C & D
      George Lewis in Japan (with combo), 1963, issued 1965 by George Buck GHB-14
      George Lewis Band of New Orleans: Jazz at Preservation Hall, 1963, Atlantic Records-1411
      Loonis [McGlohan] in London, piano with Pete Morgan (bass), 1981, Audiophile AP-166
      Marian McPartland (piano with combo), 1981, Bainbridge Records, BT-1045
      Wanted!, Marian [piano] & Jimmy [cornet] McPartland, 1977, Improv Records, -7122
      Memphis Willie B., Hard Working Man Blues, harmonica, guitar, vocal, 1961, Bluesville, -1048
      Mingus Revisited, Charlie Mingus & band, 1960, issued 1965, Trip Jazz TLP-5513
      Mingus: Oh Yeah (with combos), 1950s, reissued 1966 by Atlantic Records-1377
      Best of Jelly Roll Morton (combos with Kid Ory, Sidney Bechet, Wilbur de Paris, Bubber Miley, etc.) 1926-40, reissued 1980, RCA/Deutsche CL-43291
      Gerry Mulligan, Chet Baker (with combo), Carnegie Hall Concert, volume One, 1964, CTI-6054
    - Pierce – Yancy (Box 107)
      Billie & De De Pierce, New Orleans, Legends Live, late 1950s?, Jazzology JCE-25
      Billie & De De Pierce, Blues in the Classic Tradition, 1961, Riverside Record RLP-370
      Billie & De De Pierce, Blues & Tonks from the Delta, 1961, Riverside Record RLP-394
      Oscar Peterson, Digital at Montreux, 1979-80, issued 1980 Pablo Records d2308224
      Oscar Peterson & Stephane Grapelli, 2 LPs, 1973, Prestige P-24041
      Jess Stacy, Blues Notion, 1944, Jazz Piano Heritage Series, volume 40, Jazzology JCE-90
      Return of Roosevelt Sykes, piano/vocals with combo, 1960, Prestige Bluesville-1006
      The Blues of Arbee Stidham: Tired of Wanderin', early 1960s, Prestige Bluesville 1021
      Tampa Red, Don't Jive Me, vocals, guitar & kazoo, early 1960s, Prestige Bluesville 1043
      Art Tatum Masterpieces, volume 2 (1934 & 1937) and James P. Johnson plays Fats Waller (1944 & 1946), 2 LPs, Decca Label/MCA2-4112
      The Tatum Solo Masterpieces, volume 11, recorded 1953-55, reissued 1981, Pablo 2310864
      Art Tatum Trio ( Tiny Grimes, Slam Stewart), 1944, reissued 1983 Audiophile Records AP-88
      Golden Horn of Jack Teagarden with the bands of Louis Armstrong, Eddie Condon, Red Nichols, Adrian Rollini and Eddie Lang & Joe Venuti's All Stars, 1929-1953, reissued MCA-227
      Jack Teagarden, Think Well of Me, music of Willard Robison, 1962, Verve Records V-8465
      Henry Townsend, Tired of Being Mistreated, vocal/guitar/piano, 1961, Prestige Bluesville-1041
      Henry Townsend, Mule, 1980, Nighthawk Records 201
      Mercy Dee Walton (vocal & piano), Pity and a Shame, 1961, Prestige Bluesville 1039
      Mary Lou Williams (in trio), My Momma Pinned a Rose on Me, 1977, Pablo Records-2310-819
      Mary Lou Williams Trio, Free Spirits, 1976, Inner City Records-2043
      Mary Lou Williams First Lady of the Piano, recorded 1953, reissued 1979, Inner City IC-7006
      Teddy Wilson, Teddy's Choice, 1975, issued 1981 by Jazzology Piano Heritage, volume 36, JCE-36
      Teddy Wilson On Tour with His Trio, 1961, Charlie Parker Records PLP-809
      Mama Yancey & Little Brother Montgomery: South Side Blues, 1961, Riverside Chicago Living Legends Series OBC-508
  - Subseries 18: LP Records: Instrumentalists - Blues and Early Jazz - Compilations (mostly piano)
    - Collectors' History of Classic Jazz – Jazz at Preservation Hall, Volume 3 (Box 107)
      Collectors' History of Classic Jazz (tribal, gospel, ragtime, blues, stride), Murray Hill 927942
      New Orleans Jazz: The Flowering, 1950s, bands/combos led by Kid Clayton, Punch Miller, Billie & De De Pierce, Emile Barnes & Peter Bocage, Tony Parenti, Eureka Brass Band with George Lewis, Folkways Records FA-2465
      Heliotrope Bouquet Piano Rags, played by William Bolcom, 1971, Nonesuch H-71257
      Jazz Piano, Willie 'The Lion' Smith, Charles Bell, Earl Hines, Billy Taylor, Mary Lou Williams, 1965, RCA Masters PL-42`07
      Jazz Giants: The Piano Players, Mary Lou Williams, Beryl Booker, Erroll Garner, Johnny Guarnieri, 1955, Trip Jazz TLP-5504
      Keyboard Kings: Errol Garner/Art Tatum/Oscar Peterson, originally recorded by RCA, Camden, reissued 1976 by Pickwick/Camden ACL-7015
      Piano Rags by Scott Joplin played by Joshua Rifkin, volume 1, 1970, Nonesuch H-71248
      Piano Rags by Scott Joplin played by Joshua Rifkin, volume 2, 1972, Nonesuch H-71264
      Preservation Hall, volume 1, Eureka Brass Band/ Peter Humphrey, 1965?, Atlantic 1408
      Preservation Hall, volume 2, Jim Robinson's New Orleans Band (side 1) and Billie & De De Pierce (side 2), 1965?, Atlantic Records 1409
      Jazz at Preservation Hall, volume 3, Paul Barbarin & His Jazz Band (side 1) and Punch Miller's Bunch with George Lewis (side 2), 1965?, Atlantic Records 1410
    - Restricted photographs. Please use reproductions located within the collection. (Box 108)